<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Adri치n Moreno Pe침a 췅 Web &amp; Mobile Developer, all-around coder</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/experience/</link><description>Recent content on Adri치n Moreno Pe침a 췅 Web &amp; Mobile Developer, all-around coder</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.adrianmoreno.info/experience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>VP of Engineering &amp; Tribe Lead - SumUp</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/experience/sumup/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/experience/sumup/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="moved-to-denmark-joined-an-european-unicorn-">Moved to Denmark, joined an European Unicorn 游붃&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>After relocating from Amsterdam to Copenhagen - I joined SumUp to work in the danish headquarters as an Engineering Manager for the Accounting Squad, in the Merchant Growth Tribe. The team I joined had been part of a previous acquisition of SumUp (Debitoor): merging cultures and integrating into the overall company was a big challenge.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At SumUp I got hands-on with a more complex organizational setup and map, with a tribalized setup; and highly enjoyed the reflective &lt;a href="https://www.sumup.com/en-us/wtf-sumup-organisation/">spirit of the company when finding new ways of working&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tech Lead - VanMoof</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/experience/vanmoof/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/experience/vanmoof/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="startup-life">Startup-life&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>VanMoof is a developer and designer of urban e-bikes, with a Direct-to-consumer model.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With retail locations in Tokyo, Berlin, San Francisco, London, Paris, Taipei - I joined in the moment that the company started to shape as a scale-up - joining just before the &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/12/vanmoof-raises-13-5m-to-capitalize-on-e-bike-boom-in-wake-of-covid-19/">Series-A ($13.5M)&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/16/after-lockdowns-lead-to-an-e-bike-boom-vanmoof-raises-40m-series-b-to-expand-globally/">B ($40M)&lt;/a> investment rounds.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During my work at VanMoof I participated in in-sourcing efforts, to bring technology closer to the core of the company, especially in the digital ecosystem (which included the content and marketing sites, e-commerce systems, ERP, customer support, and other custom-developed solutions both for internal and customer use).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Technical Lead - Emakina.NL</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/experience/emakinanl/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/experience/emakinanl/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="agency-life">Agency-life&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Emakina.NL is a digital agency with a strong focus in e-commerce and enterprise content management systems. Emakina.NL is a strategic solution partner for Salesforce Commerce Cloud (&lt;a href="https://blog.emakina.com/2017/06/20/emakina-salesforce-commerce-cloud-partner/)">https://blog.emakina.com/2017/06/20/emakina-salesforce-commerce-cloud-partner/)&lt;/a>, and has also experience in cross-cloud solutions across the Salesforce ecosystem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In Emakina.NL I was part of a multidisciplinar agile team, with a cross-functional combination of roles from different providers, and the client, working together. The technical team was up to 10 people, but it was only a part of the whole - which included a dedicated QA engineering team, Product Owner, Scrum Master, and Business Analysts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CTO - Pocket Media</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/experience/pocketmedia/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/experience/pocketmedia/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="first-time-leading-a-multi-cultural-team">First time leading a multi-cultural team&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>At Pocket Media I lead the tech team of the company, in a process of product creation and launch to market. I was a member of the management team of the company, and lead up to 10 FTE, in charge of hiring, role definition, and performance management.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As part of my (team) tasks, I executed mobile and web (high scalability) development projects. I defined the products roadmap, milestones, and plans to achieve the objectives, as well as the
talent acquisition.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mobile Apps Developer - The Mobile Company</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/experience/themobilecompany/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/experience/themobilecompany/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="first-job-abroad">First job abroad&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>By 2015 I was looking for a life change - and this was accompanied by a professional &amp;ldquo;reinvention&amp;rdquo;. After years growing Zadia together with my co-founder and partner, I exited the venture with the aim of starting afresh in a new location, new culture, and discover new ways of working.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After an evaluation of potential locations where to relocate to, I chose Amsterdam as a city, and The Mobile Company as my company. There I worked with an excellent group of professionals, highly specialised in native, high quality mobile application development for some of the largest apps in the Netherlands.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Co-Founder - Zadia Software</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/experience/zadiasoftware/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/experience/zadiasoftware/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="co-founder-and-technical-lead">Co-founder and technical lead&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>At Zadia I co-Founded and bootstrapped a software development studio. From its origin as a part time job, to leading and coordinating a team of 5 engineers on the technical side.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Revenue-wise, we were doubling the revenue every year, helping make the company sustainable ant have a self-sustained growth.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The company provided software development services and advice to a range of companies, from small ones looking to digitalize their business or improve their online presence, to larger enterprise-level projects, where we would oversee the integration of multiple services, and complement the existing teams.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Programmer Analyst - Coremain</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/experience/coremain/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/experience/coremain/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="contact-with-enterprise-private-project">Contact with enterprise private project&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>After the stay at Bah칤a I wanted to check if the knowledge that I was gaining would be applicable in other companies, and I could help also setup new teams in a different environment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At Coremain I had a fruitful stay, participating in a greenfield project for a consumer bank, participating on the design and implementation of the solution that would create a new internal portal.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Programmer Analyst - Bahia Software</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/experience/bahia/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/experience/bahia/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="first-job-as-software-engineer">First job as software engineer&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>My career started in a local software consultancy company, based in Santiago de Compostela. With the main customers being large public entities and some Galician large companies, the experience was very useful to know the best practices of working in regulated environments, with strict contractual agreements.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I took part in many J2EE-based projects, helping in early phases on analysis with R&amp;amp;D proposals, and participated in its design and development, specially in early stages of the projects. I helped also open a new line of business for the company, with the development of content management systems, based on Drupal.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>