<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Fintech &amp; Business on</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/categories/fintech--business/</link><description>Recent content in Fintech &amp; Business on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 13:03:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.adrianmoreno.info/categories/fintech--business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>STOP THE PRESS 🛑</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/blog/2024-01-17-stop-the-press/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 13:03:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/blog/2024-01-17-stop-the-press/</guid><description>&lt;p>STOP THE PRESS 🛑&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(ok, now that you have stopped: share with your network and get Karma points with me :-)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I share some cool jobs from SumUp here and there. Today, I bring you THE JOB. You can join not only SumUp (cool) but our team in Copenhagen (double cool) and the Invoices Tribe (triple cool) in Bruno&amp;rsquo;s team.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are seeking a new colleague to join us as an Android developer for the Accounting squad. With a very well-located office in the center of Copenhagen, daily lunch together, and a chance to influence new product creation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>This was quite a blast. Getting so many colleag...</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/blog/2022-07-22-this-was-quite-a-blast-getting-so-many-colleag/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 22:18:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/blog/2022-07-22-this-was-quite-a-blast-getting-so-many-colleag/</guid><description>&lt;p>This was quite a blast. Getting so many colleagues from all SumUp for a week, from every discipline of Engineering, Product &amp;amp; Design, together in the same location - and having full freedom to create something together.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was really fun to be part of a team and work hands on in a new problem to solve - but it was as interesting to walk around and ask other teams what they were working. It was really energizing to see the customer centricity, and how so many of those ideas could make a real difference for our merchants!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>