<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Workplace and Culture on</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book_categories/workplace-and-culture/</link><description>Recent content in Workplace and Culture on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book_categories/workplace-and-culture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Flex: Reinventing work for a smarter, happier life</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/flex-reinventing-work-for-a-smarter-happier-life/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/flex-reinventing-work-for-a-smarter-happier-life/</guid><description>&lt;p>A guide for individuals and organizations on how to create a smarter, happier work life through flexibility and work-life balance.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>It doesn't have to be crazy at work</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/it-doesnt-have-to-be-crazy-at-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/it-doesnt-have-to-be-crazy-at-work/</guid><description>&lt;p>A guide for organizations on how to create a healthy and productive work culture. It rejects the &amp;ldquo;Silicon Valley&amp;rdquo; status quo and default ways of doing things, advocating for a more sane and people-centric approach.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rework</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/rework/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/rework/</guid><description>&lt;p>A guide for entrepreneurs and small businesses on how to be more productive and efficient.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Scaling People: Tactics for Management and Company Building</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/scaling-people/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/scaling-people/</guid><description>&lt;p>Claire was a leader in early stages of Google, and now is the COO at Stripe, since quite early also. It is a fantastic guide, very practical and full of detailed examples on how to build a massive impact company - and how to scale it. It takes a lot of attention to the people management side and covers a wide variety of topics, from crafting foundational documents to strategic and financial planning, hiring and team development, feedback and performance mechanisms. The book includes dozens of pages of worksheets, templates, exercises, and example documents to help founders, leaders, and company builders create scalable operating systems and lightweight processes that really work.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Best Place to Work: The Art and Science of Creating an Extraordinary Workplace</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/the-best-place-to-work-the-art-and-science-of-creating-an-extraordinary-workplace/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/the-best-place-to-work-the-art-and-science-of-creating-an-extraordinary-workplace/</guid><description>&lt;p>Guide for leaders on how to create a positive and productive workplace culture. The book covers a wide range of topics, including how to foster collaboration, how to create a positive work environment, how to motivate and retain top talent, and how to encourage innovation and creativity. Friedman draws on research from the fields of psychology, sociology, and neuroscience to provide practical strategies for creating a workplace that is engaging, rewarding, and fulfilling for employees.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Culture Map</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/the-culture-map/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/the-culture-map/</guid><description>&lt;p>A guide for leaders on how to navigate and manage cultural differences in the global business world. IT identifies eight scales on which cultures differ – communication, evaluation, trust, leadership, decision-making, communication style, time, and relationship-building – and provides practical strategies for navigating these differences in order to build strong, effective relationships with people from different cultural backgrounds. The book is based on the idea that cultural differences can be a source of strength and creativity, but they must be understood and managed effectively in order to unlock their full potential.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>