<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Organization Design on</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book_categories/organization-design/</link><description>Recent content in Organization Design on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book_categories/organization-design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Accelerate: The Science of Lean Software and DevOps: Building and Scaling High Performing Technology Organizations</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/accelerate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/accelerate/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The book draws data from the largest study of high-performing software organizations to identify key practices that contribute to software delivery performance. Its aim is to help organizations improve the speed and quality of their software development. The practices recommended include investing in infrastructure and automation, empowering teams, and using data to drive decisions. The book provides practical guidance on how organizations can adopt these practices in order to accelerate their software development and delivery.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Brave New Work</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/brave-new-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/brave-new-work/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;An exploration of alternative ways of organizing companies - focusing on how to create more adaptive and human organizations in the face of complexity and uncertainty. Dignan argues that the traditional way of working based on hierarchy, bureaucracy and control is outdated and ineffective. Instead, it proposes a new operating system (OS) for work that is based on principles such as autonomy, experimentation, transparency and purpose. It has good practical tools and examples to help with transformation - and specific industry examples (like Gore)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Scaling People: Tactics for Management and Company Building</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/scaling-people/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/scaling-people/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Claire was a leader in early stages of Google, and now is the COO at Stripe, since quite early also. It is a fantastic guide, very practical and full of detailed examples on how to build a massive impact company - and how to scale it. It takes a lot of attention to the people management side and covers a wide variety of topics, from crafting foundational documents to strategic and financial planning, hiring and team development, feedback and performance mechanisms. The book includes dozens of pages of worksheets, templates, exercises, and example documents to help founders, leaders, and company builders create scalable operating systems and lightweight processes that really work.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Team Topologies: Organizing business and technology teams for fast flow</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/team-topologies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/team-topologies/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The book is fantastic at exploring various organizational structures that can be used to build and lead effective software teams. The authors identify four main team topologies – hub-and-spoke, matrix, marketplace, and federated – and provide guidance on how to choose the right one for a given context. They also discuss the challenges and benefits of each topology and provide practical strategies for implementing and managing them. The book is aimed at software development managers and leaders looking to build and lead high-performing teams; and has very useful diagrams to map your team topologies.
I like it because it gives very useful vocabulary and visualization to how to setup a company organization - so it facilitates the dialog with other groups.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>