<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Adrián Moreno Peña · Web &amp; Mobile Developer, all-around coder</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/public-speaking/</link><description>Recent content on Adrián Moreno Peña · Web &amp; Mobile Developer, all-around coder</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.adrianmoreno.info/public-speaking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tech Leaders Journal: How to balance independence and control within your organization</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/public-speaking/tech-leaders-hub-independence-control/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/public-speaking/tech-leaders-hub-independence-control/</guid><description>&lt;p>Unlock the secrets to striking the perfect balance between independence and control within your organization with Adrián Moreno Peña, Director of Engineering at SumUp, in this episode of Tech Leaders Hub.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With over 4 million vendors relying on their products, SumUp is a leading provider of financial services for small businesses. As the Director of Engineering, Adrian leads a team of over 50 people, including 30+ engineers, responsible for the development of online invoicing and accounting tools.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the key challenges facing Adrian and his team is how to balance the need for individual growth with the needs of the larger organization. By focusing on helping others grow and succeed, Adrian has been able to foster a culture of collaboration and success within his team.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During this episode, we explored topics such as:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>How to foster a culture of innovation and sustainability within a larger organization&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The benefits of allowing smaller units to operate with a startup mentality within a company&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The importance of setting clear investments and goals for each unit&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The role of teaching and mentoring in fostering growth and development within a team&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Strategies for balancing the needs of the individual with the needs of the larger organization&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>How Can We Get More Efficient, Independent Teams?</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/public-speaking/evolution-exchange-nordics-efficient-independent-teams/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/public-speaking/evolution-exchange-nordics-efficient-independent-teams/</guid><description>&lt;p>A conversation with Olga Kryvia (Microsoft), Juan Muñoz (Pleo), and Hari Tunturivuori (Liva Healthcare) about team setup, culture - and how to create a culture where our teams depend less on us and can be self-organized.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GaliTempo · Un cliente nativo de MeteoGalicia para iOS</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/public-speaking/galitempo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/public-speaking/galitempo/</guid><description>&lt;p>Presentation for a talk about GaliTempo, a native iOS app I co-developed, that was consuming the online webservices of &lt;a href="https://www.meteogalicia.gal/">Meteogalicia&lt;/a> (the weather agency for the region of Galicia)&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>