<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title/><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/public-speaking/</link><description>Recent content on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.adrianmoreno.info/public-speaking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building trust through incident communication with Adrián Moreno, VP of Engineering at SumUp</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/public-speaking/2024-04-17-incidentio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/public-speaking/2024-04-17-incidentio/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today, good incident communication isn&amp;rsquo;t a nice to have—it&amp;rsquo;s an absolute must.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But where do you even start? To help answer that question, we sat down with the VP of Engineering at SumUp, ⁠Adrián Moreno Peña⁠, to get his perspective on how organizations of all sizes can share stellar comms no matter the situation. We discuss:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What it means to communicate during incidents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why Status Pages are critical in helping to build trust&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How you can have good comms even without a lead
&amp;hellip;and much more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item><item><title>Journey from Manager to Manager of Managers</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/public-speaking/2023-10-17-evolution-exchange-nordics-managing-managers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/public-speaking/2023-10-17-evolution-exchange-nordics-managing-managers/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;👨‍💼 With Zahid Rasheed, Head of Design &amp;amp; Development at YouSee, Adrián Moreno Peña, Director of Engineering at SumUp, and Pierre Fourgeaud, Vice President of Engineering at Airtame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🗣️ We share personal experiences, challenges faced, and strategies adopted in transitioning from a managerial role to managing multiple managers. We get into what we have learned, what we struggle with - and how we try to help our managers.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Podcast: Workplace and team culture in distributed teams</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/public-speaking/2023-07-26-distributed-teams-podcast/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/public-speaking/2023-07-26-distributed-teams-podcast/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A conversation with Majbritt and Benjamin about workplace and team culture in distributed teams. Discussing the challenges of collaborating across locations, whether remote or multi-office, and sharing learnings and practical ideas for building strong distributed teams.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tech Leaders Journal: How to balance independence and control within your organization</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/public-speaking/2022-03-17-tech-leaders-hub-independence-control/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/public-speaking/2022-03-17-tech-leaders-hub-independence-control/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Unlock the secrets to striking the perfect balance between independence and control within your organization with Adrián Moreno Peña, Director of Engineering at SumUp, in this episode of Tech Leaders Hub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With over 4 million vendors relying on their products, SumUp is a leading provider of financial services for small businesses. As the Director of Engineering, Adrian leads a team of over 50 people, including 30+ engineers, responsible for the development of online invoicing and accounting tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the key challenges facing Adrian and his team is how to balance the need for individual growth with the needs of the larger organization. By focusing on helping others grow and succeed, Adrian has been able to foster a culture of collaboration and success within his team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this episode, we explored topics such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to foster a culture of innovation and sustainability within a larger organization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The benefits of allowing smaller units to operate with a startup mentality within a company&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The importance of setting clear investments and goals for each unit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The role of teaching and mentoring in fostering growth and development within a team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strategies for balancing the needs of the individual with the needs of the larger organization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Episode available also in &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_o5XzIBtj0I"&gt;youtube with live video&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>How Can We Get More Efficient, Independent Teams?</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/public-speaking/2021-10-17-evolution-exchange-nordics-efficient-independent-teams/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/public-speaking/2021-10-17-evolution-exchange-nordics-efficient-independent-teams/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A conversation Juan Muñoz (Engineering Manager at Pleo), Harri Tunturivuori (VP of Engineering at Liva Healthcare), Olga (Ollie) Kryva (Engineering Manager at Microsoft) about team setup, culture - and how to create a culture where our teams depend less on us and can be self-organized.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Emakina.NL Meetup: A.I. for Commerce</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/public-speaking/2018-02-08-emakina-ai-commerce-meetup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/public-speaking/2018-02-08-emakina-ai-commerce-meetup/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Organized and hosted a meetup at Emakina.NL on the topic of artificial intelligence applications in commerce — exploring how AI can help generate more conversions and drive business results.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Podcast with Startup León: Performance marketing and work culture in Spain vs Netherlands</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/public-speaking/2017-03-19-startup-leon-podcast/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/public-speaking/2017-03-19-startup-leon-podcast/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A conversation (in Spanish) with Júlia and Mario from Startup León about working at Pocket Media, performance marketing, and the differences in work culture between Spain and the Netherlands.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Native Advertising</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/public-speaking/2013-04-16-pocketmedia-native-ads/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/public-speaking/2013-04-16-pocketmedia-native-ads/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Flash-talk, in &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PechaKucha"&gt;pechakucha&lt;/a&gt; format presentation, with 30 seconds per slide (12 slides total).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>🇪🇸 La web: pasado, evolución y futuro</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/public-speaking/2013-04-27-pechakucha-futuroweb/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/public-speaking/2013-04-27-pechakucha-futuroweb/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Flash-talk, in &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PechaKucha"&gt;pechakucha&lt;/a&gt; format presentation, with 30 seconds per slide (12 slides total).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>🇪🇸 Fundamentos de posicionamiento en buscadores</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/public-speaking/2013-04-24-seo-fundamentos/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/public-speaking/2013-04-24-seo-fundamentos/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Presentation (in Spanish) for a conference about e-commerce taking place in Santiago de Compostela (Galicia, Spain). In the talk I explained the basics of Search Engine Optimization. The audience were small business owners, getting interested into e-commerce to expand their business and new alternative sales channels.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>🇪🇸 PlotSpot - application to explore recording locations for movie/TV contents</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/public-speaking/2012-12-17-plotspot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/public-speaking/2012-12-17-plotspot/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Presentation (in Spanish) for PlotSpot, a native iOS app I co-developed. The app displayed a list of locations where TV shows or movies had been recorded. The idea was to consume the content while watching it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>🇪🇸 GaliTempo · Un cliente nativo de MeteoGalicia para iOS</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/public-speaking/2012-10-25-galitempo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/public-speaking/2012-10-25-galitempo/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Presentation (in Spanish) for a talk about GaliTempo, a native iOS app I co-developed, that was consuming the online webservices of &lt;a href="https://www.meteogalicia.gal/"&gt;Meteogalicia&lt;/a&gt; (the weather agency for the region of Galicia)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>🇪🇸 Cosas que (quizás) me hubiese gustado oír al acabar la carrera</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/public-speaking/2012-06-08-graduation-speech/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/public-speaking/2012-06-08-graduation-speech/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Graduation speech for the students of graduating in 2012 in Computer Engineering in my university, Santiago de Compostela. After graduating in 2007 and having started a company since then, I got the chance to participate in the graduation ceremomy with a speech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe the best thing is that I thought that the &amp;ldquo;inspirational quote&amp;rdquo; that I used to close the speech was from Steve Jobs - as I had seen attributed in Wikiquote. But it turned to be a joke added to the page - where the quote itself is from a Digimon son 🤷 (&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Butter-Fly"&gt;Butter-Fly&lt;/a&gt;, in particular).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>