<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Product, strategy and business on Adrián Moreno Peña · Web &amp; Mobile Developer, all-around coder</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book_categories/product-strategy-and-business/</link><description>Recent content in Product, strategy and business on Adrián Moreno Peña · Web &amp; Mobile Developer, all-around coder</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book_categories/product-strategy-and-business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Beyond Entrepreneurship 2.0</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/beyond-entrepreneurship-2.0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/beyond-entrepreneurship-2.0/</guid><description>A really good guide on how to create a company to perdure. The book covers a wide range of topics, including how to set the right goals, how to assemble and lead a strong team, and how to make strategic decisions that will drive growth and success. They speak out of their extensive experience as entrepreneurs and business leaders to provide practical guidance and strategies for building a successful, long-term business.</description></item><item><title>Blue Ocean Strategy</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/blue-ocean-strategy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/blue-ocean-strategy/</guid><description>A guide on how to create new markets, and compete in new areas without competition; instead of fighting for market share growth in crowded markets.</description></item><item><title>Continous Discovery Habits</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/continous-discovery-habits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/continous-discovery-habits/</guid><description>A guide for product teams on how to build a culture of continuous discovery and use data to drive decision-making.</description></item><item><title>Crossing the Chasm</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/crossing-the-chasm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/crossing-the-chasm/</guid><description>The book focuses on how to navigate the &amp;ldquo;chasm&amp;rdquo; between early adopters and mainstream customers and achieve mass market success; and how it&amp;rsquo;s key to succeed after a promising beginning with the most passionate (and forgiving) piece of the market.</description></item><item><title>Empowered</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/empowered/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/empowered/</guid><description>A really good guide for product teams on how to build effective, empowered teams that can drive innovation and deliver great products. It touches how to build a strong product culture, how to foster collaboration and communication within a team, and how to set clear goals and priorities. It provides practical strategies and insights for building and leading successful product teams.</description></item><item><title>Escaping the Build Trap</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/escaping-the-build-trap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/escaping-the-build-trap/</guid><description>A guide for organizations on how to avoid the &amp;ldquo;build trap&amp;rdquo; of constantly adding more features to their products and focus on delivering value to customers. It includes how to prioritize and validate product ideas, how to build and measure product outcomes, and how to create an organizational culture that is focused on delivering value to customers. It has quite some practical tips.</description></item><item><title>Good to Great</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/good-to-great/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/good-to-great/</guid><description>Guide for businesses on how to become great by focusing on the right goals, assembling the right team, and making the right decisions. The book presents the results of a research study that identified a set of companies that made the transition from good to great and identifies the key factors that contributed to their success. Collins provides practical guidance and strategies for businesses looking to make the transition from good to great, including how to set the right goals, how to assemble the right team, and how to make the right decisions.</description></item><item><title>Inspired</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/inspired/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/inspired/</guid><description>It focuses in agile development and lean startup concepts. It gives very good insights on how to define a product vision, how to validate product ideas through customer research and testing, and how to measure and optimize product performance. It has a very practical look - and together with Empowered serves as a really good field guide on how to setup product teams for success.</description></item><item><title>Loonshots</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/loonshots/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/loonshots/</guid><description>Its main topic is innovation, covering related topics including how to encourage risk-taking and creativity, how to identify and support promising ideas, and how to create an organizational culture that is conducive to innovation. Bahcall uses examples from a variety of fields, including science, technology, and business, to demonstrate how organizations can foster and support innovation at different stages of development. The book offers practical strategies and insights for organizations looking to foster a culture of innovation and turn promising ideas into successful ventures.</description></item><item><title>Measure What Matters</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/measure-what-matters/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/measure-what-matters/</guid><description>Guide for organizations on how to set and track progress towards key objectives using the OKR (Objectives and Key Results) framework. The book covers how to set clear, measurable goals and track progress towards them, how to align individual and team goals with company-wide objectives, and how to create a culture of accountability and continuous improvement. Doerr provides practical strategies and tools for organizations looking to implement the OKR framework and drive progress towards key objectives.</description></item><item><title>No Rules Rules</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/no-rules-rules/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/no-rules-rules/</guid><description>Based on Netflix&amp;rsquo;s story - the book gets deeper into the culture of the company, focusing on the freedom and responsibility, with the gains on high performance, innovation and growth. For that, it explains how to set clear expectations and hold people accountable, and how to foster a sense of purpose and meaning in work.</description></item><item><title>Principles: Life and Work</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/principles-life-and-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/principles-life-and-work/</guid><description>Guide for individuals and organizations on how to achieve success by following a set of principles and practices that Dalio has developed over his career. The book covers a wide range of topics, including how to set and achieve goals, how to make better decisions, and how to build and lead effective teams. Dalio provides practical guidance and strategies for individuals and organizations looking to achieve success by following a set of guiding principles</description></item><item><title>The Hard Thing about Hard Things</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/the-hard-thing-about-hard-things/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/the-hard-thing-about-hard-things/</guid><description>Guide for leaders on how to navigate and overcome challenges in business. The book covers a wide range of topics related to leadership and management, including how to make difficult decisions, how to hire and develop great teams, and how to build and scale a successful company. It&amp;rsquo;s quite straightforward, and written in a direct and easy going way.</description></item><item><title>The Lean Product Playbook</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/the-lean-product-playbook/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/the-lean-product-playbook/</guid><description>Guide for product teams on how to build and launch successful products using the principles of lean startup. The book covers a range of topics related to product development and management, including how to validate product ideas, how to build and measure product outcomes, and how to optimize product performance. Olsen provides practical strategies and tools for product teams looking to apply the lean startup framework to their work, and offers a step-by-step guide for building and launching successful products</description></item><item><title>Trillion Dollar Coach</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/trillion-dollar-coach/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/trillion-dollar-coach/</guid><description>It tells the career and management philosophy of Bill Campbell, a well-respected coach and advisor to many of Silicon Valley&amp;rsquo;s most successful tech companies. He worked and deeply influenced companies like Apple, Google, and Amazon, helping achieve significant growth and success. The book is based on interviews with Campbell and with the many executives and entrepreneurs who worked with him, and offers insights into how his coaching and mentorship helped shape the culture and strategies of some of the most successful tech companies in the world.</description></item><item><title>Zero to One: Notes on Startups, or How to Build the Future</title><link>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/zero-to-one-notes-on-startups-or-how-to-build-the-future/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.adrianmoreno.info/book/zero-to-one-notes-on-startups-or-how-to-build-the-future/</guid><description>A guide for entrepreneurs on how to create and grow successful startups. It&amp;rsquo;s mainly related with entrepreneurship, including how to identify and pursue unique business opportunities, how to build and scale a successful company, and how to overcome common challenges faced by startups. It&amp;rsquo;s based on the notes from a class that Thiel gave - so it&amp;rsquo;s very practical and to the point.</description></item></channel></rss>